



#### **PROFILE**

# **Multidisciplinary Graphic Designer.**Digital Marketing and Typography lover.

I love designing graphic elements above everything else, regardless of the support type. I've worked on logo design, brand strategies, signage design, murals and wallpaper design, editorial design, website design, and visual images for large-scale events. I have recently ventured into digital marketing strategy; I think of it as another platform to tactically objectify graphic elements.

When I work as a freelancer or join a team: I learn, connect, and actively seek creative solutions. I can bring experience, desire, and obsession for beauty.

### **EDUCATION**

- EUDE | European Business School Master's degree in Digital Marketing Expected Diploma, 2023 | Madrid, Spain
- · ISDi Higher Institute of Design | University of Havana

Bachelor's degree in Graphic Design 2007 - 2012 | Havana, Cuba

#### **EXPERTISE**

- · Brand design & Logotype design
- · Posters & Billboards
- · Typography
- · Editorial & Layout design
- · Final artwork for printing
- · Signage & Trade Show booth design
- · Merchandise
- · Web & banners design

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### GRAPHIC DESIGNER | FREELANCER | CONTRACT WORK OR SERVICE Present - 2017

- Client: Firvida & Lorenzo PA. Attorney 's Office. West Palm Beach, Florida, 2022. Scope: Creative direction, brand identity, brand board, stationery design, and final arts for printing. On-brand visual elements focused on messaging.
- Client: Jazware LLC. Fort Lauderdale, Florida, 2022. Scope: Illustrations for Instruction Manual (IM) of various products.
- Client: Anytime Home Health Corp. Tampa, Florida, 2021. Scope: Creative direction, brand identity, brand board, stationery design, and final arts for printing. On-brand visual elements focused on messaging and social media basics.
- Client: Cafe Bahia restaurant. Havana, Cuba, 2020 Scope: Brand identity, brand board, on-brand visual elements focusing on restaurant props, and final arts for printing. Social media basics.
- Client: Cuban Fund of Cultural Assets Company. Ministry of Culture. Havana, Cuba. Dates: December 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, and 2019. Scope: Visual image design for the most significant International Craft Fair (FIART) in Cuba. Graphic image design, the main poster of the event, signage, environmental graphics, stationery, and merchandising. Development of creative advertising content for various (digital and printed) media.
- \*Collaboration with designer Alejandro Rodríguez (Alucho). We were responsible for this graphic design project (FIART) for five consecutive editions.
- Client: OXFAM International Org. 2018, Havana, Cuba. Scope: Campaign logo design, graphic image, and applications for the "I am Resilient. For a safe community" campaign. Project organized in response to the damage caused by the passage of Hurricane Irma in village settlements in the central part of the island of Cuba.

### 2015 - 2016

- Client: Jose Villa Soberon sculptor. Havana, Cuba, 2016. Scope: Brand identity, brand board, web design (digital portfolio), image manipulation for use on websites, on-brand visual elements focusing on stationery, and exhibition catalogs.
- · Cuba Pavilion World Expo Milan 2015.

**Client:** Chamber of Commerce of the Republic of Cuba. 2015, Milan, Italy. **Assignment:** Responsible for planning, coordinating and implementing graphic design projects from beginning to end. **Scope:** Brand design, signage, environmental graphics for interiors, stationery, merchandising. Development of creative graphic elements and branded content for video mapping inside the pavilion.





#### **TECHNICAL & SOFT SKILLS**

Photoshop	
Illustrator	
InDesign	
After Effects	
Premier	
HTML & CSS	
Corel Draw	
Sketch Up	
AutoCad	
Office Suite	
Layout	
Layout Artworking	
•	
Artworking	
Artworking Assembly skills	
Artworking Assembly skills Production	
Artworking Assembly skills Production Flexibility	
Artworking Assembly skills Production Flexibility	
Artworking Assembly skills Production Flexibility Coworking	

### **EVENTS AND EXHIBITS**

- ONDi Design Award 2022, Graphic
  Design, Professional modality (Mention).
  May 2022, Havana, Cuba.
- 7th Edition of the Ibero-American Biennale of Design BID\_20. November 2020, Madrid, Spain.
- 5th Edition of the Ibero-American Biennale of Design BID\_18. November 2019, Madrid, Spain.
- 3rd Shenzhen International Poster Festival. August 2018, ShenZhen, China.
- 1st Havana Design Biennale BDHabana'16. May 2016, Havana, Cuba.
- XII Havana Biennale. May 2015, Havana, Cuba.

# PRODUCT GRAPHIC DESIGNER 2013 - 2014

**Company:** Proyecto Espacios, an interior design and architecture studio. Havana, Cuba.

- $\cdot$  Design of customized graphics to be produced in screen printing on chairs, concept based on the work of each of the Cuban writers recognized as National Prizes for Literature.
- · On-brand visual elements design focusing on the company's brand.
- · Responsible for planning, coordinating, and implementing graphic design projects from beginning to end in the interiors of hotel Arenal (Boca Ciega Beach, Havana); in the interiors of Literary Coffee Marquis of Arcos (Old Havana, Havana), and in the artwork presented by Proyecto Espacios studio for the exhibition of design and architecture Signs of Life in 2013.

# JUNIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER 2012 - 2013

**Company:** Cuban Fund of Cultural Assets Company. Ministry of Culture Havana, Cuba.

- · PowerPoint presentation design for weekly company meetings.
- · Editorial design, layout, and final artwork for children's books and artist catalogs.
- $\cdot$  Designs and media format for use in print and web applications, and production-ready delivers

LAST EDITED: July, 2022